

# Julio Cesar Mauro

• E-mail: juliomauro@gmail.com

LinkeIn: https://linkedin.com/in/juliomauro

• GitHUB: https://github.com/juliomauro

# PROFESSIONAL SKILLS:

As a seasoned professional with more than twenty years of experience, I had the opportunity of working for different industries such as Internet Service Providers, Banks, News Media and Tourism. I have a broad experience in operations, systems architecture and infrastructure.

Between my knowledge of open source solutions and past experiences, I am able to deliver reliable and fast low-cost solutions.

My experience managing large and complex environments allows me to identify the best practices to deliver excellent results, both independently and as part of a team.

## COMPUTER LITERACY:

- Solid technological experience on several applications as follows: VMWare, Linux, AWS virtualization, PV2, Vmotion, Storage, HA, balancer, Tunning and vSphere and its functionalities.
- On AWS environment: Large experience on EC2, EBS, Security Group, VPC, VPN, AutoScaling, Route 53, CloudWatch ELB, S3, CDN and RDS.
- On Linux environment: Solid experience with Web Servers, Varnish cache application, Wordpress Blog server, VPN, FTP server, OpenLdap implementation, IPTables security FW, MySQL database, AWStats, DHCP server, Linux Shell script coding, Phyton, Ansible, Terraform and also K8s for computer tasks automation.
- On AWS platform: Vast experience on deploying new server machines and DR environment.
   Administration of applications as follows: Balancers, Firewall, Backup, Storage and other solutions such as AKAMAI CDN configuration and testing, BIG-IP, F5 and A10 Networks balancer solutions.
   Irules, Virtual pool servers for servers loading distribution, Storage and iSCSI protocol.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## CVC Corp, Santo André / Trend Operadora, São Paulo

- DevOps on AWS and VMWare environments
- · Cloud and infrastructure coordinator

## SINCE NOVEMBER 2015

- Responsible for supervising the staff infrastructure and internal support teams caring

for the good functioning of the Company's internal and external systems.

- Responsible for the AWS environment system (EC2, EBS, Security Group, VPC, VPN,

Auto Scaling, Route 53, Cloud Watch ELB, S3, CDN e RDS), as well as for the others

infrastructure segments as follows: Backup, linux implementations and VMware.

- Gained experience on implementing: ERP based on JDE Weblogic Oracle; NoSQL Mongo Data Base.
- Technical responsible for the following projects: Segue Viagem website for business traveling,

IT infrastructure migration between sites, Enterprise backup and restore over the AWS Amazon Cloud.

- Senior on DevOPS for optimization and automation for AWS, VMware and GCP making use of Git,

Docker, Ansilble and Terraform on Linux as on Windows platforms.

- Good technical expertise on Rancher for containers management and FreeIPA.

#### Folha de S.Paulo, São Paulo

IT coordinator

## JANUARY 2013 - OCTOBER 2015

# Senior IT coordinator

- Responsible for supervising the staff's Linux and Data Base infrastructure teams caring for a good functioning of the Company's internal and external systems.
- As a coordenator, the main tasks were as follows: Reformulations and improvements of the web
- systems, server process and newspaper printing solution; migration of XEN-Virtualization

platform to VMWare / Vsphere.

- Reponsible for implementing the VMware high ability virtualization pool as well as for

redesigning the new Company's main Website, smartphone and tablet APP. e.g. Livraria da Folha,

Transfolha, Folhapress, and yet Backup and restore new infrastructure solution. Also, a new

search engine based on Sphix and Elastic search was also implemented.

- Setup, improvement and thus management of the following systems: Digital TV indexing system

for means of collection purposes; MySQL Clustering; The Brazilian 2014 Elections IT infrastructure

environment; IT infrastructure for the 2014 World Cup and not less

```
improvements on the
  Company's Help Desk monitoring platform.
```

## S.A. O Estado de S.Paulo, São Paulo

VMWare and Linux Senior Consultant.

#### MARCH 2009 - DECEMBER 2012

- As a senior IT Consultant the main tasks were as follows: Responsible for maintaining and drawing
  decisions about the Company's main news website and its infrastructure of servers over the VMware
  virtualized environment, for purposes of ITIL best practices on maintenance, improvements and
  upgrades. The achieved result was to deliver a high ability enterprise environment, cost reduction, fast
  infrastructure service deliver, fast new machines deploys and an efficient administration over the all IT
  infrastructure environment.
- Head of the NIRVANA PROJECT. (Centralized Multi Platform Host Consolidation Project over VMWare 5.0).

Technical manager for the following Company's IT projects:

- Estadão Home Website: Layout Upgrade and IT Infrastructure improvements.
- Estadão ESPN Broadcast Radio: Infrastructure implementation for the home website
- Estadão ESPN. Moving of its server machines from physical to virtual hosts.
- Mobile project: Woodwing server implementation for content deliver across mobile platform e.g.

Apple iPAD, SAMSUNG.

- Estadão Collection Deliver project: For deliver of 137 years of Company's news paper collection

over the web.

- HP iSCSI 4000 Series Storage Hardware - AKAMAI CDN - Varnish Cache for fast Apache HTTP

front-end content deliver and Real Media OAS 11 advertising banner deliver.

Other project learship were as follows:

- Divirta-se, E+, PME, Piauí, Economia, Política and Wordpress blogs.

## Sterling Commerce, São Paulo e Curitiba

· Senior Linux and GIS Consultant

## MARCH 2007 - JANUARY 2009

• I worked as a consultant for several financial companies such as Banco Itaú, Banco HSBC, Banco Votorantim, CEMIG and others, seeking and creating solutions for file interchange, data processing,

process management and consulting on the Linux / UNIX platform.

- Technical consultant responsible for the HSBC File Transfer project, joining the

HSBC payment

systems at the Brasil site, located in Curitiba.

- Technical consultant responsible for Banco Itaú's international payment project.
- Technical consultant responsible for the integration project of payments between

Banco Itaú's national banks.

- Instructor of Gentran Integration Suite (GIS) course for new Sterling Commerce consultants

and clients, working on Linux, Unix and Solaris platforms.

## **EDUCATION**

#### Kaplan International English, Toronto, Canadá

NOVEMBER 2017 - DECEMBER 2017

Intensive English to improve quickly on English fluency and learn grammar and vocabulary.

## FASP, São Paulo

FEBRUARY 2002 - NOVEMBER 2007

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

FECAP, São Paulo

FEBRUARY 1995 - DECEMBER 1997

• Data Processing Technician

## PROFESSIONAL ON JOB COMPUTER AND CERTIFIED TRAINING COURSES:

- AWS Security Fundamentals
- AWS Certified SysOps Administrator
- AWS EC2: High availability and scalable
- AWS Technical Essentials
- AWS Technical Professional
- AWS Solutions Architect
- AWS CloudFront
- AWS EC2, CloudFront and the Route53 Alura
- AWS S3: Object working out and storage on Cloud Alura
- Docker
- Git: Computer Code controlling and sharing

- VMWare NSX: The technical overview
- VMware Certified Professional
- VMware VCenter: Configuration Manager
- VMware Virtual SAN: Deploy and Manage [V5.5]
- VMware vSphere with Operations Management
- VMware vSphere: Data protection and recover fundamentals
- VMware vSphere: Fast Track [V5.5]
- VMware vSphere: Setup, Configure and Management
- VMware vSphere: Optimizing and Scaling
- Docker: Setup and management Alura
- Sophos Endpoint Cerfitied
- Cisco Executive Workshop Attendee
- Clusters and high ability on Linux Sucesu SP
- ITIL Foundation V3
- JIRA Administration
- Linux Professional Institute LPI 101 e 102

# **LANGUAGES**

- Native Portuguese
- Advanced English
- Advanced Italian